Could she be Princess Flora?
I never imagined I'd meet
her in a place like this.
Sir Rio?
Thank you so much for saving
us from our predicament.
My name is Liselotte Cretia.
I serve as the governor of Amande.
My name is Haruto.
Haruto?
Sir Rio, this is Her Highness Princess Flora,
second princess of the Beltrum Kingdom.
And this is the current head of the
ducal house of Huguenot, Lord Gustav.
Princess Flora, is something wrong?
What? Oh...
If I may be so bold as to ask,
have I committed some discourtesy?
No, it isn't that. It's...
Have we met somewhere before?
Myself and Your Highness?
I don't believe so.
I see.
If Princess Flora believes she's seen you,
then are you a noble from some other land?
Or perhaps...
No, I am simply a wanderer, traveling from
place to place, training in swordwork.
I am not the sort of person who could ever
hope to be granted an audience with royalty.
I see.
To think there would be a
swordsman of such skill hiding here,
unaffiliated with any nation...
Spirit Chronicles 2
I borrowed Miharu's!
I'm wearing it properly, aren't I?
What do you think?
It suits you really well!
Lynchpin of Memories
Master Haruto?
I knew it! It is you,
isn't it, Master Haruto?
You're...
I helped you at the Ricca Company
while you were shopping! I'm Chloe!
Oh, Miss Chloe!
Thank you so much for your help back then.
Do you know him, Chloe?
Yes! He came to the main shop in Amande and
I was the one who looked after him there!
Really? I didn't realize that
you were a patron of our shop.
Allow me to say thank you for that as well.
Yes.
How kind of you. Thank you.
Hey!
I'm Sakata Hiroaki.
I happen to be a Hero!
Sakata? Is he Japanese?
So you're the Hero I've
been hearing rumors about.
I'm the real thing!
I'm delighted to have the honor
of encountering a real Hero.
My name is Haruto.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
It seems like you're a
pretty decent swordsman.
That was some good fighting out there.
I'm honored you think so.
Still, all of you are so far above my station
that I must admit I feel nervous.
My! Someone who fought a minotaur without
hesitation feels nervous because of us?
Well, it doesn't seem like there's
anything for us to do here.
Flora, Rohanna, let's move
to a carriage that works.
Of course.
Can he converse normally because
of some sort of Hero ability?
Um...
Flora!
Coming!
Did she realize who I am?
I think I'm all right with Miss Rohanna,
but Princess Flora...
It doesn't matter.
Liselotte Cretia. I've just met one
of Galarc's most influential nobles.
Please, allow me to help you somehow.
Oh, no, Master Haruto,
we couldn't ask that of you.
For example... that carriage.
With your permission,
I might be able to repair it.
Repair... that carriage?
In that case, we should at least ascertain
its condition. Aria, you come, too.
Miss Aria? That's her?
Once we're out of this forest,
we'll be in Amande.
Haruto, there is a big battle
being fought over there.
That's... Aria?
Do you know her?
Y-Yes. She's a friend from
my time at the academy.
She's wearing a Ricca Company uniform.
Now that I think about it,
I have heard that Aria serves the
daughter of the ducal house of Cretia.
I sense the presence of a powerful monster.
Aria!
Aishia, will you take the professor
somewhere safe for me?
I will.
What? Rio!
Please stand back a little.
You truly are wonderfully skilled.
It's all thanks to this sword.
In the battle earlier, you controlled
the wind with that blade.
It's an enchanted sword, isn't it?
And it's ancient artifact-class at that.
Yes.
Though the truth is that
I'm using Spirit Arts.
Still, he was quite strong
and dashing, wasn't he?
It simply isn't fair that you know
someone as wonderful as him, Chloe.
Introduce me to him later, won't you?
He and I aren't so close
that I could introduce you.
What's this?
Don't tell me you're trying
to arrange it so that you're
the only one he's friendly with?
No! I wouldn't do that.
Cosette, you're putting Chloe
in a difficult position.
Am I? But Natalie, you're curious
about him too, aren't you?
W-Well...
And it's because you're such a late bloomer
that you haven't had a single sweetheart yet.
What? Well, that's because unlike
you, I don't think more is better.
Yes, all right. Enough of that.
Please pass the drinks out, everyone.
Lady Liselotte, the emergency repairs
to the carriage are complete.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
To think that that carriage
could be brought back like this.
Thank you, Master Haruto!
Master Haruto!
Please have something
to drink, if you'd like.
It's fruit water.
I made a sweeter blend especially for you,
in the hopes it might ease your fatigue.
Thank you. I most gratefully accept, um...
I serve Lady Liselotte as a
lady-in-waiting. My name is Cosette.
Thank you, Miss Cosette.
You are most welcome.
And now, I will excuse myself.
Everyone who serves Lady Liselotte
seems to be very demure.
Demure? No, I mean...
Thank you for saying so.
Now, how shall we move this?
Move aside, please.
Now, just watch.
That'll do it, I think.
Nothing to it.
I'd expect no less of you, Sir Hiroaki.
He has an incredible
amount of magical energy.
Now, everyone, prepare to depart!
Um, is it truly all right
for me to ride in here?
There is no need for such restraint.
You saved us from our predicament.
We owe you a debt of gratitude.
It's just as he says.
When we arrive in Amande,
I'd like to thank you more formally.
No, no! Please lift your head, Lady Liselotte!
Yeah, he's right.
Someone as impressive as you shouldn't
bow her head to others so easily.
I do beg your pardon.
Well, you do seem to possess
the bare minimum of manners,
so I, the Hero, grant you
permission to ride with us.
I'm honored.
Spirit Chronicles 2
And so!
We are done with Strahlian
language studies for today!
You've all gotten very good at it!
All right! I'm brilliant!
It's not that you're brilliant. It's that
our teacher is good at teaching. Right?
Oh. You're right.
Masato!
Let's go fishing.
Okay!
What? What about your Spirit Arts training?
I'll do it some other time.
Hey!
Honestly, all he does is go and play!
Well, thanks to the magic artifacts,
he can keep up the beast children.
It's probably so much fun,
he can't help himself.
All right!
Well, using a magic item counts
as Spirit Arts training, too.
Now, then! Work hard at
your training, you two!
We will!
That's right. Concentrate on
what's right in front of you.
Oh, that's too bad!
Miharu-oneechan, you're amazing!
I'm no good at all.
No, that's not true.
Why can't I do this? What's different?
Is it just... talent?
All right, that's all for today!
Good work, both of you.
Why don't we go and have some tea?
Yes.
I'm going to go take a little walk.
Here you go!
Yay! Food!
I brought your food! Here you go!
Thank you!
Nom, nom, nom.
That was yummy! More please!
No! You have to chew properly when you eat.
What?
You have to listen to Mother.
Haru-kun.
Mii-chan.
I guess I have to, then!
Let's play again, okay?
Yes.
No matter what, okay?
We'll always, always be together!
Yeah!
No!
No! I don't like it! I don't want you to go!
You said we'd always be together! Liar!
Aki... I'm sorry!
Oniichan! You liar!
Aki-chan?
What's wrong? Why are you here all alone?
Oh, um... There were some children
playing house and they were just so cute.
Huh? They're gone.
They must have gone home.
Why don't we head back, too?
Masato seems late, doesn't he?
Maybe they went pretty far while playing.
That Masato... When we first got here,
he was startled by everything!
Well, everything was so unusual to us.
Now that I think about it, what was it
like for you and Haruto-san, Latifa-chan?
What? Um...
Well, at first... I suppose
things were a little difficult.
Difficult how?
Back then, I really acted unforgivably!
We told you about the barrier around the
village that keeps humans away, didn't we?
Master Rio was camping there
and when we approached...
we discovered Latifa there, and she'd
been made to sleep using Spirit Arts.
We thought that he'd kidnapped
a child of the village
and so we restrained Master Rio.
Oniichan had used
Spirit Arts to help me.
Back then, I often had nightmares.
Once the misunderstanding had been cleared up,
we hurried to help Master Rio.
Which reminds me... I remember
Master Rio saying something in his sleep.
Oh, yes. And I think he
may have cried a little.
Um, what did Oniichan say?
Well, if I remember correctly...
Mii-chan!
It was "Mii-chan."
What?
Mii-chan?
I'm back!
Look what I caught! It'll be great for dinner!
It's a large one, isn't it?
Yes?
Good evening.
There's both od and mana in the air!
Were you practicing Spirit Arts?
Oh... yes.
Big Sis Miharu, you sure
work hard, don't you?
Not really.
What brings you here all together?
Actually, it's about Aki...
It feels so good, doesn't it?
Yes.
About what we were talking about earlier...
Yeah?
Latifa-chan, what did you and
Haruto-san do before you came here?
Huh?
Well, I, um...
I was a slave to a noble in Beltrum.
A slave... What?
A lot happened...
but it was Oniichan who
freed me from slavery.
And then he brought me here to this village.
He said that since there are
other beast people here,
I should be able to live in peace.
Um... I'm sorry I asked
about such awful things.
No, it's all right!
Because I met Oniichan!
I went through all those hard things
so that I could meet Oniichan.
That's how I feel now.
That's why, next time,
I want to save Oniichan.
I completely understand
how you feel, Latifa-chan.
When I was little,
someone I loved betrayed me.
I was so sad and so lonely.
But then, one day, my mom remarried and
I got a new older brother and little brother.
Takahisa-oniichan and Masato.
My big brother is so kind, and he's
helped me with all sorts of things.
That's why, next time,
it's my turn to help him!
But instead I keep getting frustrated
because I'm not good at Spirit Arts...
and I start feeling awful because of
things I remember from the past...
All I do is get angry
at Masato. I'm terrible.
Aki-chan, you're thinking
about so many things
that your heart and mind can't take any more.
You've had so much to learn in your new
way of life. It must have been rough.
So if you're ever worried about anything,
tell me. Like you did just now.
I'll listen to everything you have to say!
Latifa-chan... But are you really sure?
Of course! We're friends, after all!
Okay?
Yes.
Oh! But listening might be the only
thing I'll be able to do for you.
That's enough. I'm so happy.
Thank you, Latifa-chan.
It looks like Aki is going out
to practice again this morning.
She's been working really hard lately.
Then we should, too!
Honestly.
Huh? This smell is...
Good morning, Aki!
Welcome back from morning practice.
Orphia-san! Wait... is that a uniform?
I borrowed Miharu's!
Am I wearing it properly?
What? Yes.
Orphia-san, you look lovely!
Thank you.
I'm so jealous!
I want Oniichan to see me wearing that.
It might be a little big for you, Latifa.
In this area, for example.
What? Oh, don't say that.
But why are you wearing a uniform?
Because I wanted to wear something
special to serve a special breakfast.
A special breakfast?
Apple pie!
It looks delicious!
I love apple pie!
But why would you make something
special so suddenly? Wait...
We all made it together while you
were out practicing this morning!
Miharu taught us the recipe.
According to Big Sis Miharu,
we made it very well!
Here. It's just out of the oven.
We should eat it while it's still warm.
Everyone... Thank you!
It's so good!
I just love the
sweet-tart combination!
When Masato wakes up,
he's going to be so happy!
I want Oniichan to be able to eat this, too!
Yes, we should make one for
Haruto-san! Oh, I know!
What do you think?
How adorable!
It suits you really well!
Aki-chan, your uniform fits her perfectly.
Yes! You look so cute!
Thank you, Aki-chan!
When Oniichan gets back, I'm going to show
off how I look in this uniform for him!
Proxia Empire, Imperial Capital, Nidguard
Emperor Nidol Proxia
Hey there, Nidol. How are you?
This is tedious.
Does that mean you're itching for a war?
Doesn't matter.
I've heard new of something troublesome
happening in the Beltrum Kingdom.
It would be inconvenient for Duke Arbor
to crumble right now, wouldn't it?
As a sign of our friendship,
I've sent him a goodwill ambassador.
Nothing would be resolved by internal conflict.
I'm amazed you'd do that for a
country that's doomed to ruin.
I've been looking for you, Master Lucius.
Oh, dear. Speak of the goodwill
ambassador and he appears.
Actually, I'd like your
assistance with something.
Really?
I intend to put my plan
into action, at long last.
But I've encountered a certain irregularity.
It is a truly troublesome one and a
minotaur poses it no challenge at all.
Really?
Oh, Master Nidol, your assistance
will not be required.
You do tend to stand out, you see?
Huh.
So, what is it you want me to do?
Abduct an important person.
The target is the second princess of
the Beltrum Kingdom, Flora Beltrum.
Sir Rio...
Next Time
Intruders
"Intruders."
Spirit Chronicles 2
Yay!
Illustration: Minazuki Futago